Mss.B.L493
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence, 7.0 Linear feet 17 upright boxes, 1 oversized folder, 1 digital record. (Box 1-17)
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Feb. 26, 1859; 8x5; Bailliere, C. E.
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers Concerning publications on natural history. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Feb. 26, 1859; 8x5; Littell, John S. (John Stockton), 1806-1875
    Germantown, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers) Concerning E. Littell's request for plates for his publication. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, March 2, 1859; 7-1/2x4-1/2; D'Urban, W. S. M.
    Montreal, A.L.S. 6p. (see Le Conte papers.) Coleoptera collected in Canada. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to J[ohn] M. Le Conte, Philadelphia, March 3, 1859; 8x5; Dow, John M.
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers Forwards natural history specimens. Friendly letter. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], March 15, 1859; 7-1/4x4-1/2; D'Urban, W. S. M.
    Montreal, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Canadian coleoptera. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, March 15, 1859; 7-1/2x4-3/4; Harrison, Joseph, 1810-1874
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Regrets he cannot join him and Osten-Sacken. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, March 16, 1859; 6-1/4x4; Gill, Theodore, 1837-1914
    Brooklyn, A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning publications in the ANS. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John [L.] Le Conte, March 16, 1859; 7-1/2x4-3/4; Harrison, Joseph, 1810-1874
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Is sorry he did not receive the note of last night stating that he could not join Le Conte and Osten-Sacken. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], March 16, 1859; 8x5; Ulke, Henry, 1821-
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. In German. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to Jo[h]n L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, March 21, 1859; 8x5; Dow, John M.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers Received insects. Forwards mastodon tooth. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, March 21, 1859; 7-1/2x5; Winchell, Alexander, 1824-1891
    Ann Arbor, Mich., A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Inquires if he would like to work on coleoptera of the state. Refers to other scientists who might work on other entomological subjects. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, March 25, 1859; 8x5-1/4; Bailliere, C. E.
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning a publication. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], March 26, 1859; 8x6-1/4; Harden, Jane Le Conte
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers.) Hopes he will come down to Georgia for a visit. Friendly letter. Originally B L493.4
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Philadelphia, April 1, 1859; 8x5; Cassin, John, 1813-1869
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers) Concerning the publication of one of his articles. Is proof-reading on of Henry's. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], April 5, 1859; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Lacordaire, Théodore, 1801-1870
    Liege, A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) His newest publication on entomology, which is very long, and should be off the press shortly.
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], April 5, 1859; 10x8; Le Conte, John, 1818-1891
    Columbia, S.C., A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte paper Forwards money. Social life in Columbia, S.C. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, April 8, 1859; 8x5; J.-B. Baillière et fils
    L. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning a publication. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, April 11, 1859; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Winchell, Alexander, 1824-1891
    Ann Arbor, Mich., A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning a catalogue of coleoptera of Michigan. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, April 28, 1859; 7-1/2x4-1/2; D'Urban, W. S. M.
    Montreal, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomological observations. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, May 3, 1859; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Davidson, George, 1825-1911
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Specimens being collected for him in the field of natural history of the U.S. Refers to Agassiz's son.
  - Letter to J[ohn L.] Le Conte, May 4, 1859; 8x5-1/4; Gill, Theodore, 1837-1914
    Brooklyn, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning his publication on Japanese fish. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], May 7, 1859; 8x6-1/4; Ulke, Henry, 1821-
    Washington A.L.S. 1p. In German. (see Le Conte papers.) Thanks for membership in ANS. Hopes to visit in Philadelphia soon. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, May 15, 1859; 8x5; Gibbs, George, 1815-1873
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers Entomological matters. Business.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, May 16, May 28, 1859; 5" x 8"; Motschulsky, Victor de
    St. Petersburgh, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, May 17, 1859; 10x8; Irvin, B. J. D.
    Arizona, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Notifies him of his collection of insects sent to the Smithsonian. Many coleoptera are included. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, May 27, 1859; 5" x 8"; Fiske, Willard, 1831-1904
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, May 27, 1859; 5 3/4" x 7 1/2"; Foulke, William Parker
    Philadelphia A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, June 13, 1859; 8x5; Bigler, William, 1814-1880
    Clearfield, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers Cannon comply with his request. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, June 27, 1859; 5" x 8"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    Berlin, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], July 4, 1859; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Lacordaire, Théodore, 1801-1870
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], July 28, 1859; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Murray, Andrew, 1812-1878
    Edinburgh, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Aug. 9, 1859; 5 1/4" x 8 1/2"; Murray, Andrew, 1812-1878
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Aug. 15, 1859; 7x4-1/2; Osten-Sacken, C. R. (Carl Robert), 1828-1906
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Asks that he acquire certain publications from the ANS and bill him.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Aug. 17, 1859; 9x6-3/4; Squier, E. G., (Ephraim George), 1821-1888
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Business news. Concerning the ANS.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Sept. 23, 1859; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Peirce, Benjamin, 1809-1880
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Believes the aurora borealis is the nectar of the gods, being thrown away. Thanks for the whiskey.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], Oct. 6, 1859; 8" x 10 1/2"; Osten-Sacken, C. R. (Carl Robert), 1828-1906
    St. Petersburgh, A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to John [L.] Le Conte, Oct. 7, 1859; 8 1/4" x 10 3/4"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Oct. 14, 1859; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Murray, Andrew, 1812-1878
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Oct. 15, 1859; 10x8; Davidson, George, 1825-1911
    San Francisco, Cal., A.L.S. 3p.and end. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards natural history curiosities to the ANS, including a gigantic bass.
  - Letter to John [L?] Le Conte, Oct. 21, 1859; 8 1/2 " x 10 3/4"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Oct. 28, 1859; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Kane Monument Association
    New York, A.L.S.: Sidney Kopman. 2p.on broadside. (see Le Conte papers.) Notifies him of his election as honorary member of the organization to erect a monument to Kane.
  - Letter to John [L.] Le Conte, Nov. 3, 1859; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
  - Letter to [J.L. ?] Le Conte, Nov. 3, 1859; 5" x 8"; Thomson, James
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Nov. 4, 1859; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Agassiz, Alexander, 1835-1910
    San Francisco, Cal., A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers.) Has been Collecting insects for him all summer.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Nov. 4, 1859; 8x5; Dawson, John William, Sir, 1820-1899
    Montreal, A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers Forwards Canadian coleoptera for cataloging, since Baird told him to do so.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Nov. 5, 1859; 8x5-1/4; Flint, Charles Louis, 1824-1889
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Tells him of the deadline for corrections and notes for the publication on insects, although he [Le Conte] is responsible for coleoptera only.
  - Letter to [J.L. ?] Le Conte, Nov. 5, Nov. 6, 1859; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    Berlin, A.L.S. 6p.
  - Letter to W. L. Martier, Nov. 11, 1859; 8x5-1/4; Binney, W. G. (William Greene), 1833-1909
    Burlington, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Mollusks. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Dec. 4, 1859; 5 1/4" x 8 1/2"; Hall, James, 1811-1898
    Albany, A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Dec. 9, 1859; 8x5; Dawson, John William, Sir, 1820-1899
    Montreal, A.L.s. 4p. (see Le Conte papers Thanks for naming the coleoptera and wishes to publish the list. Informs him that they arrived safely.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Dec. 12, 1859; 8x5; Lyman, Theodore, 1833-1897
    Boston, A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers Concerning his study of ophiurans, printed in ANS.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Dec. 17, 1859; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Dohrn, C. A. (Carl August), 1806-1892
    Stettin, A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Praises him and his work on coleoptera, out wishes he would work on insects, other than American, for he cannot understand just where American insects begin and end.
  - Letter to [J.L. ?] Le Conte, Dec. 20, 1859; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Dec. 26, 1859; 8 1/2" x 11"; Frazer, John Fries, 1812-1872
  - Catalogus curculionidum ex America boreali, quae im museo Universitatis exstant, Dec. 27, 1859; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Maklin, F. W.
    Helsingfors, D.S. 2p. In Latin, (see Le Conte papers.)
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Philadelphia, Dec. 27, 1859; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Maklin, F. W.
    Helsingfors, A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology. Refers to Osten-Sacken.
  - Letter to [J.L. ?] Le Conte, Dec. 29, 1859; 5" x 8"; Du Chaillu, Paul B., (Paul Belloni), 1835-1903
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Dec. 29, 1859; 6 1/2" x 8"; Xántus, Janos, 1825-1894
    Santiago, L. Calif., A.L.S. 7p.
  - Letter to [John Eatton?] Le Conte, Dec. 31, 1859; 8x5; American Geographical and Statistical Society
    New York, L. 3p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning society business.
  - Letter to John [L.] Le Conte, Jan. 4, 1860; 8x5; Lyman, Theodore, 1833-1897
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers) Concerning ophiurans.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Jan. 12, 1860; 8x5-1/2; Thomson, James
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Wishes to Purchase insects. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John [L?] Le Conte, Jan. 12, 1860; 4 1/2" x 7"; Clark, Hamlet, 1823-1867
    London, A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to John [L.] Le Conte, Jan. 20, 1860; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878
    Smithsonian inst., A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to[J.L. Le Conte], Jan. 23, 1860; 5" x 8"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Feb. 15, Feb. 27, 1860; 8x5-1/4; Motschulsky, Victor de
    St. Petersburg, A.L.S. 4p. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning entomology. Refers to Osten-Sacken. On same sheet is letter from Motukulsky to Haldeman; [Feb,15/27, 1860].
  - Letter to [Samuel Stehman] Haldeman, Feb. 15, Feb. 27, 1860; 8x5-1/4; Motschulsky, Victor de
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) Friendly letter. Wishes they had met when he was in Europe. One same sheet as letter from Motukulsky to Le Conte; Feb. 15/27, 1860.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, May (?) 9, 1860; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], June (?) 6, 1860; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Murray, Andrew, 1812-1878
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Feb. 1, 1860; 6 1/2" x 8"; Prime, Frederick
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Feb. 20, 1860; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Prime, Frederick
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning Dr. Hayes proposed exploration.
  - Letter to W[illia]m J. Taylor, March 4, 1860; 8x5; Nott, Josiah Clark, 1804-1873
    Mobile, Ala., A.L.S. 3p. Partly in pencil. (see Le Conte papers.) Regrets he has received the action of trustees which were sent to him [Taylor].
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, March 5, 1860; 8x5; Peirce, Benjamin, 1809-1880
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers Concerning positions of higher education in the U.S. Refers to Agassiz. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, March 12, 1860; 8x5; Holbrook, John Edwards, 1794-1871
    Charleston, S.C., A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers Concerning the death of Hallowell.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, March 15, 1860; 8x5-1/4; Thomson, James
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Is publishing on coleoptera. Entomological news.
  - Note to [John L.] Le Conte, Philadelphia, March 20, 1860; 2x3-1/2; Scherzer, Karl, Ritter von, 1821-1903
    A.N.S.on calling card. 1p.and add. (see Le Conte papers.) Introduces an entomologist, Felder.
  - Letter to [J.L. ?] Le Conte, March 28, 1860; 4" x 6 1/2"; Thomson, James
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Details of a case of Haemola gerosis, April 8, 1860; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Schwant, Gustaf William
    D. 9p. (see Le Conte papers.)
  - Letter to [J.L. ?] Le Conte, April 13, 1860; 5 3/4" x 9"; Felder, Cajetan, Freiherr von, 1814-1894
    Vienna, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, April 14, 1860; 8x5; Bayley, James Roosevelt, 1814-1877
    Newark, A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers Concerning the illness of his father.
  - Letter to [John Eatton Le Conte], April 14, 1860; 8x5; Le Conte, John L. (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
    Columbia, S.C., A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers Sorry he is ill. Affectionate letter.
  - Letter to [John E. LeConte], Apr. 14, 1860; LeConte, Joseph, 1823-1901
    Regarding John E. LeConte's "feeble health."
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], April 14, 1860; 8x5; LeConte, Joseph, 1823-1901
    Columbia, S.C., A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte Papers Congratulations on his forthcoming marriage. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to John L. LeConte, Apr. 14, 1860
  - Letter to John L. LeConte, Apr. 14, 1860; Newark, Bishop of
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, April 17, 1860; 5 1/2" x 9"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    B[erlin], A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], April 17, 1860; 6 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Xántus, Janos, 1825-1894
    Cape San Lucas, L. Calif., A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, April 22, 1860; 8x5; Eustis, Henry Lawrence, 1819-1885
    Cambridge Mass., A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte Papers) Congratulations on his forthcoming marriage and hopes to meet the bride.
  - Letter to John L. Leconte, Philadelphia, April 24, 1860; 10x7-3/4; Alvarado, Léon, 1818-1870
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.,on broadside,of 2p.,and add., end. In Spanish. (see Le Conte papers.) Is leaving the U.S. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, April 25, 1860; 7x4-1/2; Holbrook, H. P.
    Belmont, A.L.S. 5p. (see Le Conte papers.) Thanks for his letter about Holbrook's health. Congratulates him on his marriage Refers to J.E. Le Conte's health. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Dr. [J.L.] Le Conte, April 26, 1860; 3 1/2" x 5 1/2"; Dickson, Samuel Henry, 1798-1872
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, May 4, 1860; 7-3/4x5-1/4; Graham, Thomas L.
    Astoria, Wash., A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Congratulations him on his forthcoming marriage. Concerning the election in the Geographical Society and he and Bache were not elected.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, May 4, 1860; 4 3/4" x7 1/4"; Hammond, William Alexander, 1828-1900
    Fort Mackinac, Mich., A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], May 4, 1860; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Harden, Jane LeConte
    Orangeburg, A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers.) Congratulations on his marriage.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, May 10, 1860; 7x4-1/2; Boardman, Henry A. (Henry Augustus), 1808-1880
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Returns volume for the present, since he cannot examine it.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, May 12, 1860; 7x4-1/2; Gould, Benjamin Apthorp, 1824-1896
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers.) Congratulates him on his marriage. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], May 31, 1860; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Lacordaire, Théodore, 1801-1870
  - Letter to [J.L.?] Le Conte, June 3, 1860; 5 3/4" x 8 3/4"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, June (?) 10, 1860; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Dohrn, C. A. (Carl August), 1806-1892
    Stettin, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], June 25, 1860; 5 1/4" x 8"; Osten-Sacken, C. R. (Carl Robert), 1828-1906
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, July 2, 1860; 8x5-1/4; Say, Lucy Way Sistaire, 1801-1886
    Newburgh, A.L.S. 5p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning Ord's memoir on Thomas Say.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], July 3, 1860; 5 1/4" x 8 1/2"; Brendel, Emil
    Peoria,III., A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, July 21, 1860; 5 1/4" x 8"; Motschulsky, Victor de
    St. Petersbourg, A.L.S. 3p. In French.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, July 24, 1860; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Clark, Hamlet, 1823-1867
    London, A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) His publications consist of European insects. Is interested in those of the U.S.
  - Letter to [John L. LeConte], July 26, 1860; Putzeÿs, Jules, 1809-1882
    Written in French.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Aug. 1, 1860; 7x4-1/2; Hewitt, A. H. S.
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) sorrow at the illness of his father.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Aug. 5, 1860; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Putzeÿs, Jules, 1809-1882
    Brussels, A.L.S. 4p. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) Wants publications on insects. Lists publications wanted, among which is one of the APS. Refers to Lacordaire.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Aug. 10, 1860; 7-1/2x5; Clemens, Brackenridge, 1826-1867
    Easton, Penna., A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers.) Critical letter of Sharswood. Asks questions about him.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Sept. 3, 1860; 8x6-1/4; Shumard, B. F. (Benjamin Franklin), 1820-1869
    Austin, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Will collect Texas coleoptera for him.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Sept. 15, 1860; 5" x 8"; Sharswood, William, 1836-1905
  - Letter to his uncle [John Eatton Le Conte], Sept. 18, 1860; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Le Conte, John L. (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
  - Letter to [John E. LeConte], Sept. 18, 1860; LeConte, Joseph, 1823-1901
  - Letter to [John Eatton Le Conte], Sept. 24, 1860; 8x6-1/2; Le Conte, Josephine
    Orangeburg, S.C., A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Enjoyed their visit, and remember his face from the window as they left. Family letter.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Sept. 24, 1860; 6 1/2" x 8"; Xántus, Janos, 1825-1894
  - Letter to [J.L.?] Le Conte, Sept. 25, 1860; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Sept. 26, 1860; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Putzeÿs, Jules, 1809-1882
    Brussels, A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning publications for Lacordaire.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Sept. 28, 1860; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Motschulsky, Victor de
    St. Petersburg, A.L.S. 4p. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) Congratulates him on marriage. Concerning coleoptera. Entomology.
  - Letter to [John Eatton Le Conte], Oct. 20, 1860; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Le Conte, John L. (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
    Columbia, S.C., A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers.) Sorrow at his illness. Friendly letter
  - Letter to [John E. LeConte], LeConte, Joseph, 1823-1901
  - Letter to Dr. [J.L. Le Conte ?], Nov., 1860; 5" x 8"; Agassiz, Alexander, 1835-1910
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Nov. 7, 1860; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Xántus, Janos, 1825-1894
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards him coleoptera, collected expressly for him.
  - Letter to her uncle [J.L. Le Conte ?], Nov. 12, 1860; 5" x 8"; Le Conte, Josephine
    Columbia, A.L.S. 4p.
  - Resolution of regret at the death of John E. Le Conte, Nov. 22, 1860; 10x8; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Thos.Stewardson, Secy. 2p (see Le Conte papers.) Enclosded originally with letter of Stewardson to J.L.Le Conte; Nov. 22, 1860.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Nov. 22, 1860; 8x5; Stewardson, Thomas, 1807-1878
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Enc. (see Le Conte papers.) Encloses resolution on death of J.E. Le Conte, by ANS. For resolution, see: ANS. Resolution... Nov.22,1860.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Nov. 24, 1860; 7-1/2x5; Clemens, Brackenridge, 1826-1867
    Easton, Penna., A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Regrets death of his father.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Nov. 18, [1860]; 5" x 7 3/4"; Frazer, John Fries, 1812-1872
    A.L.S. 1p. Death of [John Eatton Le Conte]
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Nov. 27, 1860; 8x5; Taylor, William J. R. (William James Romeyn), 1823-1891
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers Sorrow at the death of his father.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Nov. 30, 1860; 5" x 8"; Dana, James Dwight, 1813-1895
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Dec. 1, 1860; 5" x 8"; Foulke, William Parker
  - Letter to [J.L.?] Le Conte, Dec. 1, 1860; 5" x 8"; Hammond, William Alexander, 1828-1900
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], Dec. 7, 1860; 7-1/4x5-3/4; Stevens, Ann LeConte
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers.) Sorrow at the death of J.E. Le Conte.
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], Dec. 12, 1860; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Le Conte, John, 1818-1891
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Dec. 20, 1860; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Harden, M.
    Savannah, A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Smallpox in the family. Concerning his forthcoming marriage. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Helen [S. Grier Le Conte], 1860; 6-1/2x4; Grier, W. P.
    Peoria, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Sends a shirt as a pattern. Concerning Peoria.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, [1860]; Graham, James Lorimer, 1831-1876
    A.L.S.with initials. 2p.and enc.of 2 items. Various sizes. (see Le Conte papers.) News of the election at the Geographical Society.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, Jan. 5, 1861; 8x5; Bayley, James Roosevelt, 1814-1877
    Newark, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers Cannot attend his marriage.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Jan. 8, 1861; 5" x 8"; Hammond, William Alexander, 1828-1900
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], Jan. 10, 1861; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; LeConte, Joseph, 1823-1901
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], Jan. 15, 1861; 5" x 8"; Osten-Sacken, C. R. (Carl Robert), 1828-1906
    Washington, [ca. ?] A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Jan. 21, 1861; 5 1/4" x 8"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Feb. 14, 1861; 7x4-1/2; Clark, Hamlet, 1823-1867
    London, A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards his publication on entomology Concerning difficulties in further work.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], March 4, 1861; 5" x 8"; Agassiz, Alexander, 1835-1910
  - Letter to J. L. Le Conte, March 21, 1861; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Carnier, Frederic
    Dijon, France, A.L.S. 3p. and add. In French.
  - Letter to John [L.?] Le Conte, March 26, 1861; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Gibbs, George, 1815-1873
    Smithsonian inst., Washington, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], April 3, 1861; 5" x 8"; Osten-Sacken, C. R. (Carl Robert), 1828-1906
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], April 10, 1861; 10x8-1/2; Chapin, F.
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) Questions on entomology.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, April 11, 1861; 5" x 8"; Hammond, William Alexander, 1828-1900
    Note on original folder regarding date of letter: